<level type="section">
  <num>4-561.15</num>
  <heading>Sexual Assault Victim Rights Task Force.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2014, the OVS shall establish a Sexual Assault Victim Rights Task Force to study nationally recognized best practices and develop recommendations regarding:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The development and implementation of an effective mechanism for submitting, tracking, and investigating complaints regarding the handling of, or response to, a sexual assault report or investigation by any agency or organization involved in the response;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether a need exists for additional sexual assault victim advocates. If a need is identified, the Task Force shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Develop criteria to certify sexual assault victim advocates;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Create a plan for how the District, in conjunction with nonprofits, can provide additional sexual assault victim advocates to meet the needs identified; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Determine the cost of funding such a plan;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether a need exists to expand the right to a sexual assault victim advocate beyond the hospital and law enforcement interview settings, such as meetings and conversations with prosecutors. If a need is identified, the Task Force shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Identify where the need exists and to what extent; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Make recommendations on how best to fill that need, whether legislatively or otherwise;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether a need exists to expand the right to a sexual assault victim advocate to juvenile sexual assault victims. If a need is identified, the Task Force shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Identify where the need exists and to what extent; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Make recommendations on how best to fill that need, whether legislatively or otherwise.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be comprised of representatives from the following entities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>DC Sexual Assault Coalition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DC SANE program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DC Victim Assistance Network;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>SART; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A District of Columbia-based college or university; provided, that the representative at that institution provides direct victim services to sexual assault victims;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>At least one governmental or agency-based victim services program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>At least 2 organizations for which the primary purpose of the organization is to provide services, education, or outreach to underserved populations disparately impacted by sexual assault; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Other entities as determined by the OVS.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By September 30, 2015, the Task Force shall produce a report that includes the results of the assessments, developments, and recommendations completed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, to be transmitted to the Council and the SART.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Task Force shall disband after the report has been transmitted to the Council and the SART.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 20, 2014, D.C. Law 20-139, ยง 215, 61 DCR 5913.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-139</heading>
      <text>See note to ยง 4-561.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
