<level type="section">
  <num>10-308</num>
  <heading>Athletic Field Permit Coordination Committee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days of February 26, 2015, the Department shall establish an Athletic Field Permit Coordination Committee (“Committee”) to advise the Department on how to develop a collaborative permitting system for athletic fields located on property owned by the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Committee shall include representatives from the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Department;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Department of General Services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia Public Charter School Board; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The National Park Service.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Department shall assign an employee from the Department to perform duties, including the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Coordinating and securing a location for Committee meetings;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Ensuring administrative support for the Committee, such as circulating meeting notices and keeping meeting minutes; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Developing an agenda for meetings and ensuring that the Committee issues the comprehensive report described in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By March 31, 2015, the Committee shall transmit to the Mayor and to the Council, and make publicly available, a comprehensive report containing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An analysis of public field availability throughout the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An analysis of whether it is feasible to create a singular office for permitting public athletic field space located throughout the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A recommendation of how to proportionately allocate permit revenue to the District government entities whose fields are being used, as opposed to all funds being deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A list of underutilized public fields that the Department, in collaboration with the Department of General Services, may convert to usable and sustainable fields.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By March 31, 2016, and each year thereafter, the Committee shall transmit to the Mayor and to the Council, and make publicly available, a report containing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An update on the progress of the analysis conducted and recommendations provided in previous reports created by the Committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Actions taken by the Committee in the preceding year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for methods to develop and provide a collaborative permitting system for athletic fields owned by the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-246, § 7b, as added Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  6072, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 10-246, § 7b, see §  6082 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 10-246, § 7b, see §  6072 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 10-246, § 7b, see §  6072 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the “Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor’s signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
