<level type="section">
  <num>32-152</num>
  <heading>Transportation benefit program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By January 1, 2016, a covered employer shall provide at least one of the following transportation benefit programs to its employees:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A pre-tax election transportation fringe benefits program that provides commuter highway vehicle, transit, or bicycling benefits consistent with section 132(f)(1)(A),(B), and (D) of the Internal Revenue Code at benefit levels at least equal to the maximum amount that may be deducted for those programs from an employee’s gross income pursuant to section 132(f)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An employer-paid benefit program whereby the employer supplies, at the election of the employee, a transit pass for the public transit system requested by each covered employee or reimbursement of vanpool or bicycling costs in amount at least equal to the purchase price of a transit pass for an equivalent trip on a public transit system; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Employer-provided transportation at no cost to the covered employee in a vanpool or bus operated by or for the employer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 302, 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>See note to § 32-151.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor's notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(c) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 302(a) of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014, and that § 302(b) of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
