<level type="section">
  <num>32-151</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Covered employer” means an employer with 20 or more employees; provided, that the Mayor may issue rules pursuant to § 32-153 to expand the definition to include employers with fewer than 20 employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Employee” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-1002(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Employer” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-1002(3).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Transit pass” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 132(f)(5)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code,  approved July 18, 1984 (98 Stat. 877; 26 U.S.C. § 132(f)(5)(A)) (“Internal Revenue Code”), and shall include transit passes for travel by bus, streetcar, or train by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, Maryland Area Regional Commuter, Virginia Railway Express, or the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Vanpool” means a “commuter highway vehicle” within the meaning of 26 U.S.C. § 132(f)(5)(B) of the Internal Revenue Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 301, 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>Law 20-142, the “Sustainable DC Omnibus Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 2014, and July 14, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-142 became effective on Dec. 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(c) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 301 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
