<level type="section">
  <num>31-651.03</num>
  <heading>Posting of policies on the Internet.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any provision of ยง 31-651.02, standard property and casualty insurance policies and endorsements that do not contain personally identifiable information may be mailed, delivered, or posted on the insurer's website. If the insurer elects to post insurance policies and endorsements on its website in lieu of mailing or delivering them to the insured, the insurer shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Ensure that the policy and endorsements are accessible and remain that way for as long as the policy is in force;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>After the expiration of the policy, archive its expired policies and endorsements for a period of 5 years and make them available upon request;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Post the policies and endorsements in a manner that enables an insured to print and save the policy and endorsements using programs or application that are widely available on the Internet and free to use;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Provide the following information in, or simultaneous with, each declaration page provided at the time of issuance of the initial policy and any renewals of that policy:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A description of the exact policy and endorsement forms purchased by the insured;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A method by which the insured may obtain, upon request and without charge, a paper copy of their policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The Internet address where the policy and endorsements are posted; and</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Provide notice, in the format preferred by the insured, of any changes to the forms or endorsements, the insured's right to obtain, upon request and without charge, a paper copy of the forms or endorsements, and the Internet address where the forms or endorsements are posted.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-201, ยง 4, 61 DCR 12565.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-201</heading>
      <text>See note to ยง 31-651.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
