<level type="section">
  <num>50-301.25a</num>
  <heading>Accessibility of digital dispatch for individuals with disabilities.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By January 1, 2016, a company that provides digital dispatch shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Ensure that the company’s websites and mobile applications are accessible to the blind and visually impaired and the deaf and hard of hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide a report to the Council’s Committee on Transportation and the Environment, or its successor committee with oversight of for-hire vehicles, on how the company intends to increase access to wheelchair-accessible public or private vehicle-for-hire service to individuals with disabilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A company that provides digital dispatch shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Impose additional or special charges on an individual with a disability for providing services to accommodate the individual; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require an individual with a disability to be accompanied by an attendant. “(c) If an operator accepts a ride request through digital dispatch from a passenger with a disability who uses a mobility device, upon picking up the passenger, the operator shall stow the passenger’s mobility equipment in the vehicle if the vehicle is capable of stowing the equipment. If a passenger or operator determines that the vehicle is not capable of stowing the equipment, the company that provides digital dispatch shall not charge a trip cancellation fee or, if such fee is charged, shall provide the passenger with a refund in a timely manner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an operator accepts a ride request through digital dispatch from a passenger with a disability who uses a mobility device, upon picking up the passenger, the operator shall stow the passenger’s mobility equipment in the vehicle if the vehicle is capable of stowing the equipment. If a passenger or operator determines that the vehicle is not capable of stowing the equipment, the company that provides digital dispatch shall not charge a trip cancellation fee or, if such fee is charged, shall provide the passenger with a refund in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, §  20f-1, as added Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-197, § 2(h), 61 DCR 12430.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-197</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-301.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-197: Section 7 of D.C. Law 20-197 provided, in part, that §§ 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the act shall apply as of March 10, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
