<level type="section">
  <num>7-761.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Community-based services" means non-residential specialized or generic services for the evaluation, care, and habilitation of persons with intellectual disabilities, in a community setting, directed toward the intellectual, social, personal, physical, emotional, or economic development of a person with an intellectual disability. The services shall include, but not be limited to, diagnosis, evaluation, treatment, day care, training, education, sheltered employment, recreation, counseling of the person with an intellectual disability and his or her family, protective and other social and socio-legal services, information and referral, and transportation to assure delivery of services to persons of all ages with intellectual disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Consumer" means a resident of the District of Columbia who is receiving, or eligible to receive, services from the Department on Disability Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Department" or "DDS" means the Department on Disability Services established by § 7-761.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>"DHCF" means the Department of Health Care Finance as established by § 7-771.02.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"DHS" means the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department on Disability Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Habilitation" means the process by which a person is assisted to acquire and maintain those life skills which enable him or her to cope more effectively with the demands of his or her own person and of his or her own environment, including, in the case of a person committed under § 7-1304.06a, to refrain from committing crimes of violence or sex offenses, and to raise the level of his or her physical, intellectual, social, emotional, and economic efficiency. The term "habilitation" includes, but is not limited to, the provision of community-based services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Home and community-based services waiver" means a Medicaid home and community-based services waiver approved under section 1915(c) of the Social Security Act, approved August 13, 1981 (95 Stat. 809; 42 U.S.C. § 1396n).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7A)</num>
    <text>"Intellectual disability" or "persons with intellectual disabilities" means a substantial limitation in capacity that manifests before 18 years of age and is characterized by significantly below-average intellectual functioning, existing concurrently with 2 or more significant limitations in adaptive functioning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Medical Assistance Program" and "Medicaid Program" mean the program described in the Medicaid State Plan and administered by the DHCF pursuant to § 1-307.02(b), and Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>"Resident of the District of Columbia" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 7-1301.03(22).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>"RSA" means the Rehabilitation Services Agency within the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 102, 54 DCR 818; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 15(a), 59 DCR 5567; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5002(a), 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-169, in (1), substituted "persons with intellectual disabilities" for "persons with mental retardation" in the first sentence, substituted "person with an intellectual disability" for "person with mental retardation" in the first and second sentences, and substituted "intellectual disabilities" for "mental retardation" at the end of the second sentence; added (7A); and repealed (10) and (11), which formerly read: "(10) 'Mental retardation' or 'persons with mental retardation' means a substantial limitation in capacity that manifests before 18 years of age and is characterized by significantly subaverage intellectual functioning, existing concurrently with 2 or more significant limitations in adaptive functioning. (11) 'MRDDA' means the former Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Administration within the Department of Human Services."</text>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-155 added (3A); repealed (8); and substituted "DCHF" for "Medical Assistance Administration" in (9).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 102 of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006, 54 DCR 1155).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-264</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-264, see notes following § 7-761.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the "Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
