<level type="section">
  <num>7-761.07</num>
  <heading>Medicaid services.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department and DHCF shall enter into an agreement for the Department to direct: policy development and design of services, rate-setting, and support provided under the Home and Community-Based Services Waiver for Individuals with Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities or any other waiver targeted for people with intellectual and developmental disabilities and their families that is approved under section 1915(c) of the Social Security Act, approved August 13, 1981 (95 Stat. 809; 42 U.S.C. § 1369n); and policies, services, and supports related to the operation of intermediate care facilities for individuals with intellectual disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall affect the status of the DHCF as the single state agency for the administration of the Medicaid Program under section 1902(a)(5) of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 344; 42 U.S.C. § 1396a(a)(5)).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 107, 54 DCR 818; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 15(c), 59 DCR 5567; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5002(d), 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-169 substituted "intellectual or developmental disabilities" for "mental retardation" in (a).</text>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-155 rewrote (a); and substituted "DCHF" for "Medical Assistance Administration" in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 107 of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006, 54 DCR 1155).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5002(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-264</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-264, see notes following § 7-761.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>See note to § 7-761.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>See note to § 7-761.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
