<level type="section">
  <num>4-261.03</num>
  <heading>LIHEAP Heat and Eat initiative.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish a LIHEAP Heat and Eat initiative for the purpose of providing the maximum standard utility allowance to all participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All food stamp program recipients shall be automatically enrolled in the LIHEAP Heat and Eat initiative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All LIHEAP Heat and Eat participants shall receive a minimum annual benefit of $ 20.01.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Participation in the LIHEAP Heat and Eat initiative shall not preclude any recipient from receiving standard LIHEAP benefits for which he or she is eligible.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 5083, 57 DCR 181; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5052, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-155 substituted “$ 20.01” for “$ 1” in (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5083 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5083 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 4-261.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the “Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor’s signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
