<level type="section">
  <num>5-129.71</num>
  <heading>Reimbursable police escorts and other law enforcement services.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may charge and collect reimbursement fees, as set forth in the fee schedule established pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, for providing police escorts that are necessary to protect public health and safety. All reimbursement fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the fund established by § 47-2826(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ 2-501 et seq.], shall issue rules setting forth a reimbursement fee schedule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “police escort” shall include the assignment of law enforcement personnel and vehicles as necessary to ensure the preservation of public safety, typically either at a specified location or from a point of origin to a specified destination, in a manner consistent with the nature of the persons, material, and the threat posed by the movement or event.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 3002, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see §  3002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see §  3002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see §  3002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the “Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor’s signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.K95+K151</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
