<level type="section">
  <num>47-4304.01</num>
  <heading>Defined tax credit related to IRS income adjustments.</heading>
  <text>A taxpayer whose taxable income was changed or corrected by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1997, and ending before January 1, 2001, shall be allowed a tax credit equal to the decrease in the District tax for the applicable years; provided, that:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The changed or corrected taxable income was based on a federal income tax provision to which District tax law conforms;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The District has not previously adjusted the taxpayer's return to encompass the change or correction;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The tax credit shall be applied over a 3-year period in equal amounts in tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2019.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The credit shall be without overpayment interest; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>In each year in which the credit is taken on a return, the taxpayer shall notify the Office of Tax and Revenue by designating on that return the tax type or types to which the credit shall apply for that year.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-85, § 2(b), 61 DCR 184; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7002, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-155 rewrote (3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(i) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Law 20-179, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by D.C. Law 20-155, § 7002, see § 2(j) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-85</heading>
      <text>Law 20-85, the "Tax Clarity Equity Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-348. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 2013, and December 3, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-255 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-85 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the "Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
