<level type="section">
  <num>2-539</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the following terms shall have the same meanings as provided in § 2-502:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Adjudication";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Agency";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Council";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"District";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Mayor";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Order";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Party";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Person";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Proceedings";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Public record";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Relief";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Rule"; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Rulemaking".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Critical infrastructure" means existing and proposed infrastructure systems and assets, whether physical or virtual, so vital to the District of Columbia or the United States that the incapacity or destruction of the infrastructure system or asset could jeopardize the physical security, economic security, health, safety, or welfare of the public.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Critical infrastructure information" means information not customarily in the public domain that is related to the security of critical infrastructure of companies that are regulated by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia, including information regarding:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Actual, potential, or threatened interference with, attack on, compromise of, or incapacitation of critical infrastructure or protected systems by either physical or computer-based attack or similar conduct (including the misuse of or unauthorized access to all types of communications and data transmission systems) that violates federal or District of Columbia laws, harms interstate commerce of the United States or the economy of the District of Columbia, or threatens public health or safety;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The ability of any critical infrastructure or protected system to resist such interference, compromise, or incapacitation, including any planned or past assessment, projection, or estimate of the vulnerability of critical infrastructure or a protected system, including security testing, risk evaluation, risk-management planning, or risk audit; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any planned or past operational problem or solution regarding critical infrastructure or protected systems, including repair, recovery, reconstruction, insurance, or continuity, to the extent it is related to such interference, compromise, or incapacitation.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1968, Pub. L. 90-614, title II, § 209, as added Mar. 25, 1977, D.C. Law 1-96, § 2, 23 DCR 9532; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-160, § 2(b), 61 DCR 10735.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-1301.52.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-1529.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 1-1529.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-160 designated the existing provisions as (a) and rewrote (a); and added (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Critical Infrastructure Freedom of Information Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-71, February 22, 2014, 61 DCR 27).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Critical Infrastructure Freedom of Information Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-229, November 29, 2013, 60 DCR 16788, 20 DCSTAT 2630).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Critical Infrastructure Freedom of Information Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-285, February 20, 2014, 61 DCR 1603).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Critical Infrastructure Freedom of Information Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-459, Oct. 24, 2014, 61 DCR 11374, 20 STAT 4364).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Critical Infrastructure Freedom of Information Third Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-580, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1264, 21 STAT 730).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-96</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-96, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-531.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-160</heading>
      <text>See note to § 2-534.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
