<level type="section">
  <num>47-2712</num>
  <heading>Electrical fees.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall amend from time to time the schedule of fees to be charged by the District of Columbia for the inspection of electrical equipment and for the issuance of permits to perform electrical services. The Mayor shall amend the schedule by rule to provide for fees in amounts as in his judgment will defray the approximate costs of performing inspections and issuing permits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Until the schedule of fees is amended by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, the schedule of fees to be charged by the District of Columbia for the inspection of electrical equipment and for the issuance of permits to perform electrical services is as follows:</text>
    <text>@@TABLE@@</text>
    <level>
      <heading>A refund of permit fees shall be made as follows:REFUNDS</heading>
      <level>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>When no work has been done under authority of a permit, the fee in excess of the costs of inspection to verify no work having been done, based on $13 per inspector hour, the cost of any engineering examination time previously devoted to approval of plans based on $20 per hour, plus $19 administrative costs of "issuance and refund", shall be refunded 19.00</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>When work authorized by permit has been only partially done and when the District is satisfied that no more work will be done under the permit, the fee in excess of the cost of any engineering plans examination based on $20 per hour, cost of inspections made, based on $13 per hour, plus $19 administrative costs of "issuance and refund", shall be refunded 19.00</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Provided, that the request for refund shall be made within six months from the date of issuance and the permit and receipt are returned to the Permit Branch.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>The penalty for a permit to abate notice of doing work without a permit shall be 50 percent of the fee.PENALTY</heading>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>No permit fee shall be charged when supported by evidence indicating that the applicant is under contract or subcontract to perform the following:WAIVER OF PERMIT FEES</heading>
      <level>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Work done exclusively for the District of Columbia.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Work done under contract for the District of Columbia.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Work done exclusively for agencies of the United States government.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title III, § 301, 23 DCR 2461; June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 202(a), 30 DCR 2632; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other officers, licensing and registration fees, Mayor's power to fix, see § 1-301.74.</text>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other officers, Mayor's power to increase or decrease fees authorized in § 1-301.74, see § 1-301.75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-301.74.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2712.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 47-2212.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-82</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-82, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2702.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 5-14</heading>
      <text>Law 5-14, the "District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1983," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 5-74, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 12, 1983 and April 26, 1983, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 4, 1983, it was assigned Act No. 5-29 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 1102 of D.C. Law 5-14 provided that the Mayor shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
