<level type="section">
  <num>28-4202</num>
  <heading>Rulemaking.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue rules to implement this chapter, including rules establishing radon screening, testing, or mitigation programs in the District that are in compliance with any recommendations or guidelines published by the United States Environmental Protection Agency. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules by resolution within the 45-day period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ 2–501 et seq.].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue emergency rules, without prior Council approval, which shall be effective for not more than 120 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 13, 1993, D.C. Law 9-183, § 2(b), 39 DCR 8206; Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 201(b), 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28-4202.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-142, in (a), substituted “issue rules to implement this chapter, including rules” for “issue proposed rules” in the first sentence, and deleted the former second sentence which read: “The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day review period, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess.”</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 9-183</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-183, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-4201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28-4201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(b) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 201 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
