<level type="section">
  <num>28-4201</num>
  <heading>Proficiency requirement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person or company shall conduct or offer to conduct radon screening, testing, or mitigation in the District for a fee unless the person who performs the service has been:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Listed as proficient by the Environmental Protection Agency to offer radon screening, testing, or mitigation services; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has received a certificate of proficiency from an organization approved by the Mayor to offer radon screening, testing, or mitigation services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall maintain, revise as necessary, and make available to the public a list of persons or companies who have been listed as proficient by the United States Environmental Protection Agency to offer screening, testing, or mitigation for radon.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 13, 1993, D.C. Law 9-183, § 2(b), 39 DCR 8206; Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 201(a), 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28-4201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-142 rewrote (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-183</heading>
      <text>Law 9-183, the "Radon Contractor Proficiency Act of 1992," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-69, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 7, 1992, and October 6, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 2, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-303 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-183 became effective on March 13, 1993.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>Law 20-142, the "Sustainable DC Omnibus Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 2014, and July 14, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-142 became effective on Dec. 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(b) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 201 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
