<level type="section">
  <num>48-311</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Food access” means the ability of an individual or a family to consistently obtain affordable, nutritious food equitably across geography and income level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Food assets” means any resource or capacity, whether physical or skill-based, in the growth, production, processing, distribution, disposal, or repurposing of food.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Food desert” means an area where more than 50% of the population is at or below 185% of the average median income level and where an individual cannot obtain a wide selection of fresh produce and other nutritious foods within ½ of a mile of the individual’s residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Food procurement” means the purchasing of or contracting for large volumes of locally grown food either directly from farms or from vendors by large entities either public or private, including schools, hospitals, and prisons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Local food economy” means an individual, organization, or business that maintains a presence in the District and is involved in the growth, production, processing, distribution, disposal, or repurposing of food within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Locally grown” means from a grower in Delaware, the District, Maryland, New Jersey, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Virginia, or West Virginia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Urban agriculture” means the practice of growing, cultivating, processing, and distributing vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, herbs, nuts, seeds, and rootstock within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-191, § 2, 61 DCR 12160.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-191</heading>
      <text>Law 20-191, the “Food Policy Council and Director Establishment Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-821. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 7, 2014, and Oct. 28, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor’s signature on Nov. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-483 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-191 became effective on Mar. 10, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
