<level type="section">
  <num>1-1162.09</num>
  <heading>Rules.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Ethics Board, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ 2-501 et seq.], shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this subchapter, including rules for the administration of preliminary investigations, formal investigations, and hearings related to violations of the Code of Conduct or other provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Ethics Board shall submit to the Council for its consideration proposed legislation amending §  1-1161.01(7) to establish a revised Code of Conduct, which shall be explicitly applicable to all employees and public officials serving the District of Columbia, its instrumentalities, subordinate and independent agencies, the Council of the District of Columbia, boards and commissions, and Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, but excluding the courts.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Ethics Board shall issue rules to implement the provisions of a comprehensive Code of Conduct established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 209, 59 DCR 1862; July 15, 2014, D.C. Law 20-122, § 2(c), 61 DCR 5688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-122 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Comprehensive Code of Conduct and BEGA Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-323, Apr. 28, 2014, 61 DCR 4681).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 19-124</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-124, see notes under § 1-1161.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-122</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1161.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
