<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.331</num>
  <heading>Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of transfers from the Potomac Electric Power Company to facilitate cost-sharing for the District of Columbia Power Line Undergrounding (“DC PLUG”) initiative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to pay for any purpose authorized by the Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Financing Act of 2014, effective May 3, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-102; D.C. Official Code § 34-1311.01 et seq.), for the DC PLUG, initiative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned , shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of the fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 7, 2015, D.C. Law 20-178, § 2, 62 DCR 864.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) establishment of the Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG, see §  2 of the Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG Establishment Temporary Act of 2014 (D.C. Law 20-178, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 864).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) establishment of the Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG, see §  2(a) of the Pepco Cost-Sharing Fund for DC PLUG Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-509, Dec. 8, 2014, 61 DCR 12719, 20 STAT 4431).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
