<level type="section">
  <num>2-211.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Pay-for-success contract" means a contract between the District and a social service intermediary that establishes outcome-based performance standards for social programs performed by nonprofit service providers and initially funded by private investors through a social impact funding instrument and provides a mechanism by which investors shall receive a return of their investment and earnings thereon only if outcome-based performance standards are met by the social service intermediary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Social service intermediary" means an organization that is organized and operated pursuant to section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3)), or an affiliated legal entity thereof that is so organized and operated and that is capable of entering into a pay-for-success contract with the District that sets forth outcome-based performance standards, contracting with service providers to deliver social services, raising capital to finance the delivery of social services via a social impact funding instrument, and administering the social impact funding instrument by providing ongoing investor relations and project management.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Social impact funding instrument" means an investment product established by a social service intermediary to raise private investment capital for social programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1132, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 1132-1134 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 1132-1134 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 1132-1134 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the "Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
