<level type="section">
  <num>2-1210.31</num>
  <heading>Emerging Business District Demonstration Projects.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall authorize the creation of Emerging Business District Demonstration Projects for business development purposes and provide financial assistance, beginning in fiscal year 2016, for up to 5 years while a business tax base is further established. These funds shall be distributed through a grant program by the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for these funds, applicants must demonstrate property owner commitment to the program through matching grants of at least 25% of the proposed program's total budget.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Business Improvement Districts with budgets under $1 million as well as eligible 501(c)(3) and 501(c)(6) organizations may apply and be awarded these funds.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 45 days of February 26, 2015, the Mayor shall publish draft regulations regarding the criteria and awarding of grants; provided, that if no regulations are published, organizations will be entitled to apply as of November 1, 2015.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Regulations shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The ability to establish and assemble a panel of reviewers for applications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A formula to determine what level of seed funding is sufficient to establish operations and allows the pursuit of matching funds from the private sector or otherwise;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The ability for applicants to be eligible for technical assistance, training, and mentoring opportunities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Eligible uses of funds, which shall include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Economic research; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Community or business outreach.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7182, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 7192 and 7193 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 7182 and 7183 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of subchapter, see §§ 7182 and 7183 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>See note to § 32-1661.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
