<level type="section">
  <num>47-1817.07a</num>
  <heading>Tax on capital gain from the sale or exchange of a Qualified High Technology Company investment.</heading>
  <text>For tax years beginning after December 31, 2018, notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter and in lieu of the tax imposed by §§ 47-1806.03(a)(7)(A), 47-1807.02(a)(4), and 47-1808.03(a)(4), the tax on a capital gain from the sale or exchange of an investment in a Qualified High Technology Company, as defined in § 47-1817.01(5)(A), shall be at the rate of 3% if:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The investment was made after [March 11, 2015];</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The investment was held by the investor for at least 24 continuous months;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>At the time of the investment, the stock of the Qualified High Technology Company was not publicly traded; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The investment is in common or preferred stock of the Qualified High Technology Company.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-210, § 2(b), 61 DCR 13072.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-210</heading>
      <text>Law 20-210, the "Promoting Economic Growth and Job Creation Through Technology Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-945. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Nov. 18, 2014, and Dec. 2, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Dec. 22, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-514 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-210 became effective on Mar. 11, 2015.</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-210: Section 3 of D.C. Law 20-210 provided that the act, to the extent it reduces revenues below the financial plan, shall apply as of January 1, 2019, or upon the implementation of the provisions in § 47-181(c)(17) in effect on March 11, 2015, whichever is later; provided, that the priority list in § 47-181(c) is maintained.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
