<level type="section">
  <num>8-651.04</num>
  <heading>Preservation of Special Trees; permits; penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person or nongovernmental entity, without a Special Tree removal permit issued by the Mayor, to Top, cut down, remove, girdle, break, or destroy any Special Tree.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue a Special Tree removal permit under this section where the applicant has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shown that the Special Tree in question is a Hazardous Tree;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shown that the Special Tree in question is of a species that has been identified, by regulation, as appropriate for removal; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Paid into the Tree Fund an amount equal to $35 for each inch of the circumference of the Special Tree in question.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A violation of subsection (a) of this section, or a failure to comply with the conditions contained in a Special Tree removal permit, shall constitute a violation subject to a fine of not less than $100 per each inch of the circumference of the Special Tree in question.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-309, § 104, 50 DCR 888; Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 421, 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-142 repealed (b)(4) and (c) and made related changes.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-309</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-309, see notes following § 8-651.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>Law 20-142, the "Sustainable DC Omnibus Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 2014, and July 14, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-142 became effective on Dec. 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(h) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 421 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
