<level type="section">
  <num>38-2061.01</num>
  <heading>Employment of retired teachers.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the salary of any retired teacher who first becomes entitled to an annuity under this subchapter after November 17, 1979, and who is subsequently employed by the government of the District of Columbia shall be reduced by such amount as is necessary to provide that the sum of such teacher’s annuity under part A of subchapter II of this chapter and compensation for such employment is equal to the salary otherwise payable for the position held by such teacher. No salary subject to this reduction shall be reduced to less than any applicable minimum wage set forth in the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1060; 29 U.S.C. § 201   et seq.), or any other applicable federal minimum wage statute or regulation.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 7, 1946, 60 Stat. 875, ch. 779, § 25, as added Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 922, Pub. L. 96-122, § 257; Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-198, § 5, 61 DCR 12450.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross references</heading>
      <text>District of Columbia retirement board, members entitled to compensation exempt from provisions of this section, see § 1-711.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section references</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-711.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 31-1245.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 31-739f.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-198 added the last sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-198</heading>
      <text>Law 20-198, the “Retirement Technical Amendments Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-440. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 7, 2014 and Oct. 28, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Nov. 26, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-491 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-198 became effective on Mar. 10, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
