<level type="section">
  <num>32-1008.01</num>
  <heading>Notice requirements for temporary staffing firms.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A temporary staffing firm shall furnish to each employee at the time of the initial interview or hire a notice that is signed and dated by the temporary staffing firm and the employee containing the information required by § 32-1008(c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of the notice:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If a specific rate of pay has not been determined at the time of the initial interview or hire, a temporary staffing firm shall provide the employee with a range of potential wages the employee will likely earn based upon the qualifications of the employee and the suitability of the assignment;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The range of potential hourly wages may not be excessively broad and must be based on a good-faith estimate of the typical wage earned by similarly qualified employees working at assignments similar to those for which the employee is eligible and likely to be assigned; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If a fixed, designated payday has not been established at the time of the initial interview or hire, a temporary staffing firm shall inform the employee that the payday may vary depending upon the usual practice at the assignment.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When a temporary staffing firm assigns an employee to perform work at, or provide services for other another organization, the temporary staffing firm must notify the employee in writing of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The specific designated payday for the particular assignment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The actual rate of pay for the assignment and the benefits, if any, to be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The overtime rate of pay the employee will receive, or, if applicable, inform the employee that the position is exempt from additional overtime compensation and the basis for the overtime exemption;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The location and name of the client employer and the temporary staffing firm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The anticipated length of the assignment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Whether training or safety equipment is required and who is obligated to provide and pay for the equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The legal entity responsible for workers’ compensation, should the employee be injured on the job; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Information about how to contact the designated enforcement agency for concerns about safety, wage and hour, or discrimination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notice provided under this section must be provided in English and in the employee’s primary language if other than English.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The term “temporary staffing firm” means a business that recruits and hires its own employees and assigns those employees to perform work at or services for another organization, to support or supplement the other organization’s workforce, or to provide assistance in special work situations such as employee absences, skill shortages, seasonal workloads, or to perform special assignments or projects.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Electronic mail, text messaging, facsimile, and regular mail shall each constitute written notice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 9a, as added Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 3(d), 61 DCR 10157.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) repeal of D.C. Law 20-157, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Law 20-240, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 20-157, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-157</heading>
      <text>See note to § 32-1002.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-157: Section 7 of D.C. Law 20-157 provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
