<level type="section">
  <num>7-755.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Commission on Health Disparities.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Commission on Health Disparities ("Commission") to prepare comprehensive recommendations to the Department of Health, the Council, and the Mayor that examine health disparities in each election ward of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have 9 voting members, who shall be appointed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Six voting members shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council, in accordance with ยง 1-523.01(f).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor's initial 6 appointments shall include 3 members appointed to 3-year terms and 3 members appointed to 2-year terms. All subsequent appointments by the Mayor shall be for 3-year terms.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Three voting members shall be appointed by the Council.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Council's initial 3 appointments shall be for 1-year terms. All subsequent appointments by the Council shall be for 3-year terms.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The voting members shall have expertise in at least one of the following areas:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Health disparities;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Social and human services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Early learning and education;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Minority communities;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Economic development; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Ecology and the environment.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall appoint the Chairperson of the Commission from among its voting members.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall have 8 nonvoting advisory members, including the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Chairperson of the Committee on Health, who shall serve as an ex-officio member;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Three community advisory members, one each from Wards 5, 7, and 8, appointed by the Council;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One patient organization representative, appointed by the voting members of the Commission; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The presidents or chief executive officers of 2 District hospitals and a representative from an insurance company who has access to a health disparities database, or their designees.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "patient organization representative" means an individual who works for a nationally or locally recognized organization committed to improving the diagnosis, treatment, and quality of life for individuals suffering from a particular disease or condition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All vacancies on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the initial appointment is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All members of the Commission shall be appointed within one year after March 10, 2015.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 192, ยง 2, 61 DCR 12403.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-192</heading>
      <text>Law 20-192, the "Commission on Health Disparities Establishment Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-572. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 7, 2014, and Oct. 28, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Nov. 21, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-484 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-192 became effective on Mar. 10, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
