<level type="section">
  <num>7-755.02</num>
  <heading>Commission duties and functions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Analyze each election ward in the city for health disparities related to the following diseases, conditions, and health indicators:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Diabetes;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Asthma;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Infant mortality, including sudden infant death syndrome;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>HIV/AIDS;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Heart disease;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Stroke;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Breast cancer, cervical cancer, and prostate cancer;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Chronic kidney disease;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Mental health;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Women's health issues;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Smoking cessation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Oral disease;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Immunization rates of children and senior citizens; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(N)</num>
        <text>Any other disease, condition, or health indicator that the Commission considers appropriate;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Gather information from public hearings, inquires, and studies to understand how the District government may work to eliminate health disparities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Seek federal grants, if available; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submit a formal city action plan by March 1st of each year to the Department of Health, the Mayor, and the Council.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The formal city action plan required by subsection (a)(4) of this section hall be a public document and shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A report of the Commission's findings regarding the prevalence and severity of the diseases, conditions, or health indicators studied that highlight the election ward and demographic most affected; possible steps that can be taken by the District government to remedy these issues; and, expected outcomes that will result from taking the recommended steps; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Draft legislation, regulations, amendments to statutes or regulations, or any other specific steps for implementing the recommendations described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 192, ยง 3, 61 DCR 12403.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-192</heading>
      <text>See note to ยง 7-755.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
