<level type="section">
  <num>25-126</num>
  <heading>On-site sales consumption permit.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The holder of a manufacturer's license, class B, may apply for an on-site sales and consumption permit in order to use a portion of the licensed premises for the on-premises sale, service, and consumption of beer brewed by the brewery and purchased by the customer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The holder of an on-site sales and consumption permit shall only sell, serve, and permit the consumption of beer brewed by the brewery and purchased by the customer between the hours of 1 p.m. and 9 p.m., 7 days a week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The on-premises sales and consumption permit shall not obviate the requirement of the holder of a manufacturer's license, class B, to obtain a tasting permit pursuant to § 25-118, to be authorized to provide samples of beer to a customer at no cost.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A violation of this section shall constitute a primary tier violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2002(c), 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>See note to § 25-110.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
