<level type="section">
  <num>10-1104.04</num>
  <heading>Enforcement; penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A violation of this subchapter or a rule issued in accordance with this subchapter shall be enforced and adjudicated pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ 2-1801.01 et seq.] ("Civil Infractions Act"). The Mayor may also enforce a violation of this subchapter or a rule issued in accordance with this subchapter pursuant to § 50-921.19(a), (c), (d), (e), and (f).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates a provision of this subchapter may be punished by a fine not exceeding $100 or imprisonment for not more than 10 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1163, Pub. L. 90-596, title IV, § 404; Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-207, § 6(b), 61 DCR 12690.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 7-1019.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 7-920.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-207 rewrote this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-207</heading>
      <text>See note to § 10-1181.06..</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-207: Section 12(a) of D.C. Law 20-207 provided that §§ 2(a), 2(b)(1), 2(b)(2)(A), 2(b)(2)(B), 2(b)(2)(C), 2(c), 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11 shall apply as of March 11, 2015.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
