<level type="section">
  <num>8-1825.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Africanized bee” means a hybrid variety of Apis mellifera produced by the cross-breeding of the aggressive African honey bee Apis mellifera scutellata with a European honey bee subspecies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Apiary” means a place where a colony is kept.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Bee disease” means an abnormal condition resulting from action by a parasite, predator, or infectious agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Brood” means the embryo and egg, larva, and pupa stages of a bee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Colony” means a hive and its equipment and appurtenances, including bees, brood, comb, pollen, and honey.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Comb” means the assemblage of cells containing a living stage of a bee at a time prior to emergence as an adult.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the District Department of the Environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7A)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the District Department of the Environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Hive” means a container used for the housing of a colony.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Honey bee” means Apis mellifera or another species designated as suitable for an urban environment by the Director.</text>
    <text>Apis mellifera</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Multi-unit building” means a building with at least 4 separate housing units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, trust, association, firm, joint stock company, organization, commission, or any other legal entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 212, 60 DCR 1300; Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 411(a), 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-142 added (7A); substituted “used” for “intended” in (8); rewrote (9); inserted “building” following “Multi-unit” in (10); substituted “legal entity” for  “private entity” in (11); and repealed (12).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 19-262</heading>
      <text>See note to § 8-1825.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>Law 20-142, the “Sustainable DC Omnibus Act of 2014,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 2014, and July 14, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-142 became effective on Dec. 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(h) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 411 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
