<level type="section">
  <num>31-3171.09a</num>
  <heading>Distribution of individual and small group health benefit plans.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A carrier that offers individual or small group health benefit plans shall offer such plans solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange, as established pursuant to §  31–3171.04(a), subject to the following transition provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Individual health benefit plans with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2014, shall be offered solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On or after January 1, 2014, small group health benefit plans offered to any small business that was not insured as of December 31, 2013, shall be offered and issued solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Small group health benefit plans offered to or renewed by any small business that was insured as of December 31, 2013, may be issued or renewed during calendar year 2014 through existing distribution channels with the same carrier or a new carrier, except that such plans shall meet the qualifications for certification of a qualified health plan as provided in section 10; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Unless the Council acts by October 1, 2014 to change the date that all small group health plans shall be offered, issued, or renewed through the American Health Benefit Exchange, on or after January 1, 2015, all small group health benefit plans shall be offered and issued or renewed solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The requirements of this section shall not apply to grandfathered health plans as defined in section 1251 of the Federal Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 2, 2012, D.C. Law 19-194, §  10(a), as added July 16, 2014, D.C. Law 20-123, § 2(c), 61 DCR 5379.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10a, concerning distribution of individual and small group health benefit plans, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-22, October 3, 2013, 60 DCR 10880).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10a, concerning distribution of individual and small group health benefit plans, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-87, June 19, 2013, 60 DCR 9542, 20 DCSTAT 1446).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10a, see §§ 2(c) and 3 of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-170, September 26, 2013, 60 DCR 14742).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10a, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-335, May 22, 2014, 61 DCR 5375).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-123</heading>
      <text>See note to § 31-3171.01.</text>
      <text>§ 31-3171.09b. Sale, solicitation, and negotiation by insurance producers.</text>
      <text>(a) An insurance producer that is licensed in the District and authorized by the Commissioner to sell, solicit, or negotiate health insurance pursuant to Chapter 11A of Title 31 [§ 31-1131.02 et seq.], may sell any qualified health plan offered in the American Health Benefit Exchange, after satisfactorily completing training developed and provided by the Authority.</text>
      <text>(b) An insurance producer shall be compensated directly by a health carrier for the sale of a qualified health plan offered in the American Health Benefit Exchange.</text>
      <text>(March 2, 2012, D.C. Law 19-94, §  10b, as added July 16, 2014, D.C. Law 20-123, § 2(c), 61 DCR 5379.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10b, concerning sale, solicitation, and negotiation by insurance producers, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-22, October 3, 2013, 60 DCR 10880).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 19-94, § 10b, concerning sale, solicitation, and negotiation by insurance producers, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-87, June 19, 2013, 60 DCR 9542, 20 DCSTAT 1446).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see §§ 2(a) and 3 of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-170, September 26, 2013, 60 DCR 14742).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-335, May 22, 2014, 61 DCR 5375).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-94</heading>
      <text>Law 19-94, the "Health Benefit Exchange Authority Establishment Act of 2011", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-2, which was referred to the Committee on Health, Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 2, 2012, and December 20, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 17, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-269 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-94 became effective on March 2, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-123</heading>
      <text>See note to § 31-3171.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
