<level type="section">
  <num>38-825.02</num>
  <heading>Environmental Literacy Program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An Environmental Literacy Program is established within the Office of the State Superintendent of Education. The Environmental Literacy Program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Coordinate the efforts of the District Department of the Environment, the District of Columbia Public Schools, the Public Charter School Board, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, the State Board of Education, the University of the District of Columbia, the Department of Parks and Recreation, the Department of General Services, and the Department of Employment Services to triennially develop an environmental literacy plan for public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establish and convene an Environmental Literacy Advisory Committee, composed of community organizations, District government agencies, and other interested persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Collect data on the location and types of environmental education programs in public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide environmental education guidance and technical assistance to public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide training, support, and assistance for environmental literacy programs in public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The environmental literacy plan shall, at minimum, include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Relevant teaching and learning standards adopted by the State Board of Education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Professional development opportunities for teachers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Suitable metrics to measure environmental literacy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Suitable methods to increase environmental literacy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Governmental and nongovernmental entities that can assist schools in the achievement of those goals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A proposed implementation method for the plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>One year after December 17, 2014, and triennially thereafter, the Environmental Literacy Program shall issue a report about the state of environmental education in the District, plans for expansion, and recommendations for improving the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 502, 57 DCR 4779; Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(j), 58 DCR 6841; Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 311(b), 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-37 designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</text>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-142 rewrote this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011,  58 DCR 6814).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 18-209</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-209, see notes following § 38-821.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 19-37</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-37, see notes under § 38-821.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>See note to § 38-821.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(e) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that § 311 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
