<level type="section">
  <num>47-181</num>
  <heading>Tax reform procedure and priority.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If local Fiscal 2015 or Fiscal Year 2016 recurring annual revenues included in the quarterly revenue estimate issued in February 2015 exceed the annual revenue estimate incorporated in the approved budget and financial plan for Fiscal Year 2015:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The first $181 million shall be recognized as Fiscal Year 2016 revenue; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any additional recurring revenue remaining after paragraph (1) of this subsection has been addressed shall be used to implement the provisions set forth in the Tax Revision Commission Implementation Amendment Act of 2014, passed on 2nd reading on June 24, 2014 (Enrolled version of Bill 20-750) ("TRC Act"), according to the priority set forth in subsection (c) of this section, for taxable years beginning or deaths occurring, as applicable, after December 31, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After the Fiscal Year 2016 budget and financial plan has been approved, any recurring revenues in a quarterly revenue estimate preceding any subsequent fiscal year, net of the dedication required by § 47-392.02(f), that exceed the local revenue incorporated in the approved budget and financial plan for that year shall be used to continue implementation of the TRC Act according to the priority set forth in subsection (c) of this section for taxable years beginning or deaths occurring, as applicable, after December 31 of the year of the applicable February estimate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The tax reform provisions of this section shall be implemented in the following priority:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reduce the rate on the new individual income tax middle bracket of $40,000 - $60,000 from 7.0% to 6.75%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Create new individual income tax brackets of $350,000 to $1 million at 8.75% and in excess of $1million at 8.95%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reduce the unincorporated and incorporated business franchise tax from 9.4% to 9.2%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reduce the rate on the new individual income tax middle bracket of $40,000 - $60,000 from 6.75% to 6.5%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Reduce the unincorporated and incorporated business franchise tax from 9.2% to 9.0%:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Raise the estate tax threshold from $1 million to $2 million;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Raise the standard deduction from $5,200 for singles, $6,650 for Head of Household, and $8,350 for married to $5650 for singles, $7,800 for Head of Household, and $10,275 for married;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Increase the personal exemption from $1,675 to $2,200;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Raise the standard deduction from $5,650 for singles, $7,800 for Head of Household, and $10,275 for married to conform to the federal level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Increase the personal exemption from $2,200 to $2,700;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Reduce the unincorporated and incorporated business franchise tax from 9.0% to 8.75%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Increase the personal exemption from $2,700 to $3,200;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Raise estate threshold from $2 million to conform to the federal level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Reduce unincorporated and incorporated business franchise tax from 8.75% to 8.5%;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Increase the personal exemption from $3,200 to $3,700;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>Reduce unincorporated and incorporated business franchise tax from 8.5% to 8.25%; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>Increase the personal exemption from $3,700 to conform to the federal level, and repeal the low income credit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Except for those provisions of the TRC Act that are funded in the approved budget and financial plan for Fiscal Year 2015, the currently unfunded provisions of the TRC Act shall not apply until their fiscal effect is provided for pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The cost of the tax policy reforms authorized by subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be recalculated on an annual basis and reported in each February revenue estimate.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(b), 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(k) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Law 20-179, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7012(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as enacted by D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(b), see § 2(l)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7012(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as enacted by D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(b), see § 2(l)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the "Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>The Tax Revision Commission Implementation Amendment Act of 2014, referenced in subsection (a)(2) of this section is subtitle B of title VIII of Law 20-155.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
