<level type="section">
  <num>1-328.12</num>
  <heading>Applicability of requirements on grants.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except where the law establishing authority for the grant exempts or modifies the requirements of this part by specific reference, any grant-making or grant-issuing authority established under D.C. Law 20-61 or D.C. Law 20-155 shall be administered pursuant to the requirements of this subchapter.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1093, 60 DCR 12472; Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1082, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-328.13.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2015 amendment by D.C. Law 20-155 added "or D.C. Law 20-155."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1093 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1093 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1082 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1082 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1082 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-301.82.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 1091 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle J of Title I of the act may be cited as the "Grant Administration Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>"D.C. Law 20-61" referred to in this section, is the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013, codified in various sections of this code.</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
      <text>"D.C. Law 20-155" referred to in this section, is the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014, codified in various sections of this code.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
