<level type="section">
  <num>38-281</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Child and Adult Care Food Program" or "CACF Program" means the program authorized by section 17 of the National School Lunch Act, approved October 7, 1975 (89 Stat. 522; 42 U.S.C. § 1766).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Child development facility" means a licensed community-based center, home, or other structure, regardless of its name, that provides care, supervision, guidance, and other services for infants, toddlers, and preschoolers on a regular basis. The term "child development facility" does not include a child development center or program that is sponsored or run by a public or private school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Eligible child" means a child who is a District resident who occupies a slot funded in whole or in part by the childcare subsidy program, authorized by § 4-402, subchapter I of Chapter 29 of this title [§ 38-2901 et seq.], or the District of Columbia Public Schools' Head Start program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Farm-to-preschool programs" means programs at child development facilities that connect early care and education settings to local food producers, as an extension of the farm-to-school model, which connect children to local foods through meals and snacks, taste tests, lessons, farmer visits, cooking, field trips, growing food, and community and parent engagement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Infant" means a child younger than 12 months of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Locally grown" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(3).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"OSSE" means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, established by § 38-2601.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"Preschool" or "preschooler" means a child older than 24 months of age but younger than compulsory school attendance age, who is not enrolled in a public, charter, or private school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Sustainable agriculture" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(9).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>"Toddler" means a child between 12 months of age and 24 months of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>"Unprocessed" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(10).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>"WIC" means the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children, as provided in section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, approved September 26, 1972 (86 Stat. 729; 42 U.S.C. § 1786).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  4072, 61 DCR 9990.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see §§ 4072-4075 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see §§ 4072-4075 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see §§ 4072-4075 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-155</heading>
      <text>Law 20-155, the "Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-750. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 28, 2014, and June 24, 2014, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Sept. 19, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-424 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-155 became effective on Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
