<level type="section">
  <num>32-1307.01</num>
  <heading>Wage Theft Prevention Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Wage Theft Prevention Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Employment Services in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of the revenue from the following sources recovered under § 32-1307:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Civil fines; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Administrative penalties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to enforce the provisions of this chapter, the Minimum Wage Revision Act, the Sick and Safe Leave Act, and the Living Wage Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 978, ch. 924, § 7a, as added Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 2(f), 61 DCR 10157.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) repeal of D.C. Law 20-157, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Law 20-240, March 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1332).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 20-157, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014, 62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-157</heading>
      <text>See note to § 32-1301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-157: Section 7 of D.C. Law 20-157 provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
