<level type="section">
  <num>48-1203</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person 18 years of age or older who commits a civil violation of § 48-1201 shall be subject to a civil fine of $25 and seizure of any marijuana and paraphernalia visible to the police officer at the time of the civil violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person under the age of 18 years who commits a civil violation of § 48-1201 shall be subject to a civil fine of $25 and seizure of any marijuana and paraphernalia visible to the police officer at the time of the civil violation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall mail a copy of the notice of violation to the parent or guardian of the person to whom the notice of violation is issued at the address provided by the person at the time the citation is issued pursuant to § 48-1202.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "civil violation" shall have the same meaning as a civil Notice of Violation for the purposes of § 16-2333(a)(1A).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, the District shall not request or impose any other form of penalty, sanction, forfeiture, or disqualification for violations of § 48-1201; provided, that this subsection does not apply to District government employers if drug use is specifically prohibited as a condition of employment, nor shall this subsection apply to Unit A of Chapter 25 of Title 7 [§ 7-2501.01 et seq.] and Chapter 45 of Title 22 [§ 22-4501 et seq.].</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-126, § 103, 61 DCR 3482.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 48-1204 and § 48-1213.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-117</heading>
      <text>See note to § 48-1201.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
