<level type="section">
  <num>8-1531</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Disposable food service ware" means containers, bowls, plates, trays, cartons, cups, lids, straws, forks, spoons, knives, napkins, and other items that are designed for one-time use for beverages, prepared food, or leftovers from meals prepared by a food service business. The term "disposable food service ware" shall not include items composed entirely of aluminum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Expanded polystyrene" means blown polystyrene and expanded and extruded foams that are thermoplastic petrochemical materials utilizing a styrene monomer and processed by a number of techniques, including fusion of polymer spheres (expandable bead polystyrene), injection molding, foam molding, and extrusion-blow molding (extruded foam polystyrene).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Expanded polystyrene food service products" means food containers, plates, hot and cold beverage cups, meat and vegetable trays, egg cartons, and other products made of expanded polystyrene and used for selling or providing food.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Food service business" means full-service restaurants, limited-service restaurants, fast food restaurants, cafes, delicatessens, coffee shops, supermarkets, grocery stores, vending trucks or carts, food trucks, business or institutional cafeterias, including those operated by or on behalf of District departments and agencies, and other businesses selling or providing food within the District for consumption on or off the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 401, 61 DCR 8045.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-142</heading>
      <text>Law 20-142, the "Sustainable DC Omnibus Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 2014, and July 14, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-142 became effective on Dec. 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-142: Section 502(f) of D.C. Law 20-142 provided that §§ 401, 402, and 406 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
