<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section>38-2801</section>
  <heading>Annual budget required.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1102, 45 DCR 7193; Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4033, 57 DCR 6242.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 31-151.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of subchapter, see §§ 702-708 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401, July 13, 1998, 45 DCR 4794), and §§ 702-708 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-564, January 12, 1999, 46 DCR 669).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 1B 1981 Ed., see §§ 702 to 708 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-41, March 31, 1999, 46 DCR 3446).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 4033 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6542).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-175</heading>
      <text>Law 12-175, the "Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-618, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 5, 1998, and June 2, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-399 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-175 became effective on March 26, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-223</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-223, see notes following § 38-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>School Based Budgeting and Accountability Act of 1998: Section 1101 of D.C. Law 12-175 provided that title XI of the act may be cited as the "School Based Budgeting and Accountability Act of 1998."</text>
      <text>§  38-2801.01. Definitions.</text>
      <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
      <text>(1) "DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools, established by § 38-171.</text>
      <text>(2) "Excess" means no longer needed for operational purposes for DCPS or another District agency.</text>
      <text>(3) "School facility" means a structure or real property that:</text>
      <text>(A) Is under the control of DCPS; or</text>
      <text>(B) Was previously under the control of DCPS or the Board of Education and is now under the control of the Mayor or another agency of the District government.</text>
      <text>(4) "Significantly underused" means a DCPS facility that is used primarily for administrative purposes and uses less than 25% of the property's available square footage on a daily basis.</text>
      <text>(5) "Swing space" means a school facility reserved for future classroom instruction or DCPS administrative use during planned renovation, modernization, or construction of another school facility.</text>
      <text>(6) "Utilization" means the ratio of current enrollment to the total number of students that can be served in a space based on programmatic and scheduling requirements.</text>
      <text>(March 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1102a, as added June 21, 2014, D.C. Law 20-114, § 3(a), 61 DCR 4669.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-114</heading>
      <text>Law 20-114, the "Comprehensive Planning and Utilization of School Facilities Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-313. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 4, 2014, and April 8, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 28, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-319 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-114 became effective on June 21. 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
