<level type="section">
  <num>38-2801.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“DCPS” means the District of Columbia Public Schools, established by § 38-171.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Excess” means no longer needed for operational purposes for DCPS or another District agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“School facility” means a structure or real property that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is under the control of DCPS; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Was previously under the control of DCPS or the Board of Education and is now under the control of the Mayor or another agency of the District government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Significantly underused” means a DCPS facility that is used primarily for administrative purposes and uses less than 25% of the property’s available square footage on a daily basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Swing space” means a school facility reserved for future classroom instruction or DCPS administrative use during planned renovation, modernization, or construction of another school facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Utilization” means the ratio of current enrollment to the total number of students that can be served in a space based on programmatic and scheduling requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(March 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1102a, as added June 21, 2014, D.C. Law 20-114, § 3(a), 61 DCR 4669.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative history of Law 20-114</heading>
      <text>Law 20-114, the “Comprehensive Planning and Utilization of School Facilities Act of 2013,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-313. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 4, 2014, and April 8, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 28, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-319 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-114 became effective on June 21. 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
